Guide to the Extra-illustrated Life of Nollekens
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
Extra-illustrated Life of Nollekens
1708-1875
1768-1836
MSS.10
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
2
6 boxes
This collection comprises an extra-illustrated copy--with many engravings and original manuscript letters--of the second edition of John Thomas Smith's Nollekens and his times, comprehending a life of that celebrated sculptor: and memoirs of several contemporary artists, from the time of Roubillac, Hogarth, and Reynolds, to that of Fuseli, Flaxman, and Blake (London: Henry Colburn, 1829).
Upcott, William, 1779-1845
Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833 ( Nollekens and his times, 1829)
Biographical / Historical
As one of the leading sculptors of his day, Joseph Nollekens (1737-1823) was responsible for immortalizing many notable contemporary figures, from Laurence Sterne and Samuel Johnson to George III and Charles James Fox. Apart from the flow of individual commissions, Nollekens also produced a line of stock busts of such figures as Wellington and Pitt. With the additional activity of sculpting church monuments--perhaps the most famous being the monument to the Three Captains in Westminster Abbey--his artistic success led Nollekens to amass a vast fortune, estimated to be £200,000 on his death.
Nollekens left a will that was eagerly awaited by a number of interested parties. It turned out to be a complex document full of codicils and different bequests. One of the people with severely dashed expectations was his future biographer, John Thomas Smith (1766-1833). By profession a topographical draughtsman and antiquary, Smith had been appointed in 1816 to succeed William Alexander as Keeper of Prints and Drawings at the British Museum. Smith had grown up almost as one of Nollekens' family, and had anticipated a generous sum from his friend; however, although he was co-executor with Francis Douce and Sir William Beechey, his bequest turned out to be a mere £100 (compared with Douce's estimated £50,000). He immediately set to work to compile a discursive biography, Nollekens and His Times (first edition 1828; reprinted 1829), which quickly came to be considered as "perhaps the most candid biography ever published in the English language" (DNB).
Apart from dealing with the central figure of Nollekens, Smith widened the scope of the biography to give an overall view of numerous other artists of the period. Foremost among these was William Blake, who received by far the largest treatment. For this reason, the work has always been highly valued, as Smith's was one of the few first-hand accounts of Blake to be published.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Item numbers (e.g. 1-179) refer to the volume and page numbers of the printed work, next to which the extra-illustrated material is placed. Item numbers beginning '3' were not interfiled in the two-volume work.
Scope and Contents
This collection comprises an extra-illustrated copy of the second edition of Nollekens and His Times, comprehending a life of that celebrated sculptor: and memoirs of several contemporary artists, from the time of Roubillac, Hogarth, and Reynolds, to that of Fuseli, Flaxman, and Blake (London, Henry Colburn, 1829). It includes two volumes, extra-illustrated with numerous letters, sketches and prints. All sheets are unbound.
The present extra-illustrated copy was compiled by the celebrated antiquary and autograph collector William Upcott (1779-1845). Upcott selected a large number of items which have a direct relevance to the work, many of them clearly having come from the collection of John Thomas Smith himself. For example, there are 26 letters to Nollekens (many on the subject of his busts), four letters by Nollekens, and three sketches by Nollekens of church monuments. In addition, there are over 50 letters to and from Smith, a number concerned with his publication or Nollekens' will, and many others dealing with paintings, prints, and contemporary scultpors and artists.
When the present copy was originally compiled, there was also an additional Blake interest in the extra material. As the son of Ozias Humphry, Upcott had possession of Blake's letters to Humphry. When the present work was offered in Upcott's sale in 1846, it seems to have been in much the condition it is now: "unbound ... most profusely illustrated with views, portraits and autograph letters ... so as to increase it to 4 vols." It then passed into the collection of Joseph Mayer of Liverpool, and was sold again at his sale in 1887, by this time "enlarged into 9 vols ... loose in boards ... and extra illustrated with about 200 autograph letters and over 450 fine portraits." At that stage it is said to have included four letters from Blake to Humphry--letters which cannot be accounted for by the three Blake-Humphry letters printed by Keynes in his edition of the collected letters, nos. 108-109 (they all seem to have a separate provenance dating from before 1887, so could not have been in the Mayer sale that year). These Blake letters have since been removed, and their present whereabouts is unknown.
There remain a number of interesting manuscript letters in the collection, including: a letter from Lord Bristol to his agent Alexander Day; a letter from Nollekens' future sister-in-law Anne Welch, about art collecting in Italy; a letter from James Forrester to Nollekens, about British painters in Italy; as well as examples of letters from artists such as Fuseli, Westmacott, Anne Damer, May Anne Flaxman, Sir William Beechey, Abraham Pether, and others. The collection also features letters from collectors, patrons, and anecdotists such as Malesworth Phillips, Richard Gregory of Colle, Charles Townley, William Seward, and Laetitia Matilda Hawkins.
A small group of additional autograph letters, mainly to Smith and concerning the biography, is found at the end of the collection. These were perhaps intended to be distributed at appropriate places in the volumes at a later date.
In addition to the autograph letters, the work has been extra-illustrated with approximately 300 engravings of people, places and works of art mentioned in the text, including portraits of many artists (Nollekens, Blake, Fuseli, Canova, Northcote, Flaxman, Barry, Rembrandt, Richard Wilson, and Paul Sandby, among others), writers and politicians. Also represented are prints of a number of busts and monuments designed by Nollekens and his contemporaries. About two-thirds or the engravings were separately published prints (some trimmed to the margins) while the remainder are extracted from publications (including eight by or after William Blake). There is also a series of unmounted prints at the end, presumably--like the unmounted letters--intended to be inserted in the text volumes when finally bound.
Almost every manuscript and extra illustration has been annotated with a small note in graphite, indicating its appropriate place in the printed work.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Paul Mellon Fund, June 2006.
Artists -- Great Britain -- Correspondence; Artists -- Great Britain -- Portraits; Artists -- Great Britain; Collectors and collecting -- Great Britain; Sculptors -- Great Britain -- Correspondence; Sculptors -- Great Britain -- Portraits; Sculptors -- Great Britain; Sculpture -- Great Britain; Wills; Engravings; Extra-illustrated copies (Provenance); Letters; Blake, William, 1757-1827; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823 -- Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833 -- Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Upcott, William, 1779-1845; British Museum
- Nollekens. Engraved by Scriven, historical engraver to His Majesty. London, published Sepr. 1, 1822, for La Belle Assemblee, no. 165., 1822 September 1; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-1)
  Scope and Contents
  Portrait of Joseph Nollekens.
  Engravings; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Untitled portrait of John Elwes., Undated; etching; 23 x 14 cm. (Box 1-iv)
  Etchings; Elwes, John, 1714-1789
- William Roscoe, Esq., R.S.L.-F.L.S. [facsimile signature] Painted by J. Lonsdale, Esq. Engraved by S. Freeman. Fisher, Son & Co. London, 1832. Proof., engraving; 19 x 13 cm. (Box 1-x)
  Portrait of Willliam Roscoe.
  Engravings; Roscoe, William, 1753-1831
- T. Banks, Sculptor R.A. Drawn and engraved by I. Conde, from a model of T. Banks. European Magazine. Published...August 1, 1791 by J. Sewell Cornhill., 1791 August 1; engraving; 21 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-2)
  Portrait of Thomas Banks.
  Engravings; Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805
- Francis Grose, Esqr. F.A.S. European Magazine. N. Dance delin. W. Ridley sculp. Published by J. Sewell Cornhill. June 1, 1797., 1797 June 1; Engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-3)
  Portrait of Francis Grose.
  Engravings; Grose, Francis, 1731?-1791
- Nathl. Smith born June 4th 1738 (from handwritten note)., undated; etching; 12.5 x 8.5 cm. (Box 1-5)
  Portrait of Nathaniel Smith.
  Etchings; Smith, N. (Nathaniel), 1738?-1809
- David Garrick Esq. Loitard Pinx. M. Ardell Fecit., undated; engraving; 20 x 16 cm. (Box 1-6)
  Portrait of David Garrick.
  Engravings; Garrick, David, 1717-1779
- British Museum, Great Russel Street. Pl. 23, undated; engraving; 12.5 x 17.5 cm. (Box 1-9)
  View of the British Museum.
  Engravings; British Museum
- Joseph Nollekens, Esq. R.A. From an original picture by F. Abbot in his own possession. Drawn by W. Evans, engraved by J. Vendramini. Published Oct. 21, 1816 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., engraving; 31.5 x 23.5 cm. (Box 1-11)
- Lord Chief Justice Mansfield., undated; engraving; 20 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-13)
  Portrait of William Murray.
  Engravings; Murray, William, 1705-1793
- Untitled and unidentified portrait., undated; etching; 21.5 x 14.5 (Box 1-14)
  Etchings
- His Majesty King George III. From an original picture by Sir William Beechey, R.A. in his own possession. Drawn by W. Evans, engraved by A. Cardon. Published March 1, 1800 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1800 March 1; engraving; 31 x 25 cm. (Box 1-15)
  Portrait of King George III.
  Engravings; George, King of Great Britain, III, 1738-1820
- Two fashion prints titled "Dress 1766" and "Dress 1738", undated; two engravings; 19 x 12 cm. (Box 1-16)
  Clothing and dress
- An Address to the Public [signed] Anthony Pogi No. 4, Orchard-street, Portman-Square., undated; clipping; 18 x 7 cm. (Box 1-20)
  Article by Anthony Pogi on fans, fan painting, and Benvenuto Cellini.
  Clippings
- Two articles on the conviction of John Rann for robbing Dr. William Bell., 1774 October 6, 20; clipping; 15 x 7 cm. (Box 1-22)
- His Majesty's State Coach. The Mirror of Literature, Amusement, and Instruction. No. 709, Saturday, March 7, 1835, Price 2d. Vol. XXV., 1835 March 7; wood engraving; 20.5 x 13.5 (Box 1-24)
  Wood engravings
- His Royal Highness William Duke of Cumberland. Benoist Sculpt., undated; engraving; 16 x 9.5 cm. (Box 1-25)
  Portrait of William Augustus, Duke of Cumberland.
  Engravings; Augustus, William, Duke of Cumberland, 1721-1765
- Richard Wilson, Esqr. Landscape painter. From an original portrait by Mengs painted at Rome 1752. Bromley Sculp., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 12 cm. (Box 1-26)
  Portrait of Richard Wilson.
  Engravings; Wilson, Richard, 1713-1782
- Richard Payne Knight, Esq. F.R.S. & S.A. From an original picture by T. Lawrence, Esq. R.A. drawn by W. Evans, engraved by E. Scriven. Published May 30, 1811 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1811 May 30; engraving; 31.5 x 26 cm. (Box 1-28)
  Portrait of Richard Payne Knight.
  Engravings; Knight, Richard Payne, 1751-1824
- Monmouth House, Soho Square. Built by the unfortunate James Duke of Monmouth, who was beheaded on Town Hill, July 15, 1685 after receiving five strokes of the axe. The house was purchased by the late Lord Bateman, was let by the present Lord, to Count de Guerchy, French ambassador, and was taken down 1773 and on the site Bateman's Buildings now stand. Published June 11, 1792 by N. Smith Gt. Mays Buildings., 1791 January 11; engraving; 25.5 x 20 cm. (Box 1-29)
  View of Monmouth House.
  Engravings
- Iaques Duc de Monmouth., undated; engraving; 14 x 8 cm. (Box 1-30)
  Portrait of James Scott, Duke of Monmouth.
  Engravings; Monmouth, James Scott, Duke of, 1649-1685
- Lithograph of letter from James Scott, Duke of Monmouth asking "My Lord" to speak to the King on his behalf. From Ringwood the 9th of July 1685. C.J. Smith, Litho., undated; lithograph; 26 x 21.5 cm. (Box 1-30)
  Lithographs; Monmouth, James Scott, Duke of, 1649-1685
- Untitled manuscript map of vicinity near the intersection of Portland Street and Mortimer Street., undated; manuscript map, watercolor over pen and ink; 15 x 10 cm. (Box 1-31)
- Two untitled clippings advertising auctions of pictures and bronzes., 1764; clippings; 16 x 6 c.m. (Box 1-35)
- Rembrandt. Rembrandt pinxt. Friedel lithog., undated; engraving; 17 x 13 cm. (Box 1-36)
  Portrait of Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn.
  Rembrandt, Harmenszoon van Rijn, 1606-1669
- Untitled fashion print depicting wig styles., undated; etching; 9.5 x 8 c.m. (Box 1-37)
  Clothing and dress; Etchings
- Marco Ricci. A. Bannerman Sculp. Vol. III p. 134., undated; engraving; 19 x 14 c.m. (Box 1-37)
  Portrait of Marco Ricci.
  Engravings; Ricci, Marco, 1676-1729
- The Residence of Sir Isaac Newton (from handwritten note)., undated; engraving; 21.5 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-38)
  View of the residence of Isaac Newton.
- Sr. Christopher Wren. Hugh Howard Esr. Sr. G. Kneller pinxt. A. Bannerman Sculp. Vol. III p. 89., undated; engraving; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 1-39)
  Portrait of Sir Christopher Wren.
  Engravings; Wren, Christopher, Sir, 1632-1723
- Jean Baptiste de Champagne. Peintre 1688. Dessines par L. Massard. Galrie Histque de Versailles, undated; engraving; 28 x 20 c.m. (Box 1-40)
  Portrait of Jean Baptiste Monnoyer.
  Engravings; Monnoyer, Jean Baptiste, circa 1636-1699
- Edward Vernon Esqr. Admiral of the White Squadron, Pub. by J. Gold 103 Shoe Lane Mar. 31, 1803. Ridley sc., 1803 March 31; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-42)
  Portrait of Edward Vernon.
  Engravings; Vernon, Edward, 1684-1757
- Poussin (Nicholas) Sculpté par Dumont fils. Gravé par Bernardi. Galrie Histque. de Versailles., undated; engraving; 30 x 20 cm. (Box 1-43)
  Portrait of Nicholas Poussin.
  Engravings; Etchings; Poussin, Nicolas, 1594?-1665
- Letter to Mr. Triphook, 1819 October 11; Yarborough, Charles Anderson-Pelham, 1749-1823; 2 pages; 8 x 14 cm. (Box 1-49)
  Asking Triphook to print off 50 copies of the enclosed list as usual.
  Correspondence
- Fragment of a legal document concerning Henry Bathurst, signed by him., 1769 November 16; Bathurst, Henry Bathurst, Earl, 1714-1794; 1 page; 8 x 20 cm. (Box 1-52)
- Craven House, Drury Lane., undated; aquatint engraving; 14 x 19 cm. (Box 1-58)
  View of the Craven House, Drury Lane.
  Aquatints
- William Earl of Craven. From a picture in Craven Buildings. Son of Sir Craven Lord Mayor of London gained great reputation as a soldier under Henry Prince of Orange of Gustavus Adolphus Keng of Sweden. He took the strong fortress of Crulznack in Germany by storm, which is one of the most extraordinary actions recorded in the history of the Great Gustavus, who knighted him as he lay wounded before the said fortress. Pubd. April 2, 1791 by N. Smith No. 18 Gt. Mays Buildings. See Granger Vol. 5 p. 210 Pennant p. 145., 1791 April 2; engraving; 25 x 20 cm. (Box 1-59)
  Portrait of William Earl of Craven.
  Engravings; Craven, William Craven, Earl of, 1606-1697
- Autograph note (third person) to Mr. West, undated; Moster, Mary, 1744-1819; autograph note; 8 x 13 cm. (Box 1-60)
  Asking him to send her a direction to Mr. Camble.
- Philip Dormer Stanhope Earl of Chesterfield. From a bust in the British Museum. I.K. Sherwin sculp. Publish'd Feby. 8th, 1777., 1777 February 8; engraving; 17 x 12.5 (Box 1-61)
  Portrait of Philip Dormer Stanhope Earl of Chesterfield.
  Engravings; Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of, 1694-1773
- Henry Fuseli. Drawn by H. Corbould from a bust by Baily. Engraved by T. Thomson. London Pubd. for the proprietors of the European Mag. by Sherwood, Jones & Co. Pater Noster Row. March 1, 1825, 1825 March 1; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-64)
  Portrait of Henry Fuseli.
  Engravings; Fuseli, Henry, 1741-1825
- Her Majesty Queen Charlotte. From an original picture by Sir William Beechey R.A. in his own possession. Drawn and engraved by W. Evans. Published March 1, 1809 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1809 March 1; lithograph; 31.5 x 24.5 cm. (Box 1-65)
  Portrait of Queen Charlotte.
  Lithographs; Charlotte, Queen, consort of George III, King of Great Britain, 1744-1818
- Lawrence. The Sleeping and the Dead are but as Pictures. Shakespeare. From a plaster-cast taken at the age of thirty-four in the possession of an attached friend. Drawn on stone by R.J. Lane, A.R.A. London. Published by Colnaghi Son & Co. April 1830. Printed by C. Hullmandel., 1830 April; engraving; 32 x 30.5 cm. (Box 1-67)
  Portrait of Lawrence.
  Lithographs
- John Boydell, Esr. ... C. Borckhardt delt. B. Smith sculpsit., undated; engraving; 30 x 24 cm. (Box 1-69)
  Portrait of John Boydell.
  Engravings; Boydell, John, 1720-1804
- John Bacon Esqr. F.A.S. Engraved by T. Blood for the European Magazine, from an original picture by Russell R. A. London, Published by James Asperne, No. 32 Cornhill 1st Feby. 1815., 1815 February 1; engraving; 21.5 x 14 cm. (Box 1-73)
  Portrait of John Bacon.
  Engravings; Bacon, John, 1740-1799
- The Right Hon: Charles James Fox. From an original picture by Sir Joshua Reynolds in the possession of the Right Hon. Lord Holland. Drawn by J. Jackson, engraved by H. Meyer. Published April 2, 1812 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1812 April 2; engraving; 32 x 26 cm. (Box 1-80)
  Portrait of Charles James Fox.
  Engravings; Fox, Charles James, 1749-1806
- John Nichols, Esq. F.S.A. Engraved by A. Cardon from an original drawing by H. Edridge., undated; engraving; 31 x 24.5 cm. (Box 1-83)
  Portrait of John Nichols.
- William Cowper, Esq. Engraved by H. Meyer from an original picture by F. Abbot, in the possession of the Revd. John Johnson, LLD. Published June 11, 1816 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1816 June 11; engraving; 32 x 25 cm. (Box 1-87)
  Portrait of William Cowper.
  Engravings; Cowper, William, 1731-1800
- Claude. From the original in the Musee Royale, Paris. Under the superintendance of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge. London, Published by Charles Knight, Pall Mall East. Engraved by W. Holl., undated; engraving; 26 x 17 cm. (Box 1-88)
  Portrait of Claude Lorrain.
  Engravings; Lorrain, Claude, 1600-1682
- J. Barry. Library of the Fine Arts, 1832. Engraved by E. Scriven from an original medallion., 1831; engraving; 15.5 x 11 cm. (Box 1-91)
  Portrait of James Barry.
  Engravings; Barry, James, 1741-1806
- Dr. Lettsom. European Magazine. Engraved by T. Holloway. Published...by J. Sewell Cornhill Juany. 1st. 1787., 1787 January 1 (Box 1-98)
  Portrait of John Coakley Lettsom.
  General
  engraving; 21 x 13 cm.
  Engravings; Lettsom, John Coakley, 1744-1815
- Paul Sandby, Esq. R. A. From an original picture by Sir William Beechey, R.A. in his own possession. Drawn by W. Evans, engraved by H. Landseer. Published Dec. 4 1809, By T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1809 December 4; engraving; 24.5 x 31 cm. (Box 1-98)
  Portrait of Paul Sandby.
  Engravings; Sandby, Paul, 1731-1809
- Hampstead Heath. Drawn by C. Stanfield A.R.A. engraved by E. Finden. See Vol. 1 p. 270., undated; engraving; 10 x 10.5 cm. (Box 1-99)
  View of Hampstead Heath.
  Engravings; Hampstead Heath (London, England)
- William Haley, Esqr. Engraved by Ridley from an original picture by Romney. Published as the Act directs by T. Bellamy at the Monthly Mirror Office King-Street Covent-Garden, April 30th, 1708., 1708 April 30; engraving; 20.5 x 13 cm. (Box 1-100)
  Portrait of William Hayley.
  Engravings; Hayley, William, 1745-1820
- Untitled engraving of a May Day dance., undated; engraving; 10 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-102)
- Monsr. Vestris Junr. in the favorite ballet (call'd) Les Amans Surpris. I. Roberts del. Published for Bells British Theatre July 20th 1781. Thornthwaite Sc., 1781 July 20; engraving; 17.5 x 11 cm. (Box 1-103)
  Portrait of Auguste Vestris.
  Engravings; Vestris, Auguste, 1760-1842
- General Paoli. Published Novr. 15, 1803 by Richard Phillips, 71 St. Paul's Churchyard., 1803 November 15; engraving; 11 x 14 cm. (Box 1-108)
  Portrait of General Pasquale Paoli.
  Engravings; Paoli, Pasquale, 1725-1807
- John Bannister Esqr. Published by J. Asperne, Cornhill, March 1, 1811. Engraved by Riley from an original painting by Drummond for the European Magazine., 1811 March 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-109)
  Portrait of John Bannister.
  Engravings; Bannister, John, 1760-1836
- Saunders Welch (from handwritten note)., undated; etching; 22.5 x 15 cm. (Box 1-112)
  Portrait of Saunders Welch.
  Lithographs; Welch, Saunders, 1710 or 11-1784
- George Lambert. J. Vanderbank pinxt. H. Robinson, sculpt. London. Published by John Major, 50 Fleet Street. Octr. 15th 1827., 1827 October 15; engraving; 23 x 15 cm. (Box 1-114)
  Portrait of George Lambert.
  Engravings; Lambert, George, 1700?-1765
- Henry Fielding Aetatis XLVIIL. Wm. Hogarth delin. Pubd. by W. Smith, 23 Lisle Street, Leicester Sq., undated; engraving; 19 x 13 cm. (Box 1-116)
  Portrait of Henry Fielding.
  Engravings; Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754
- Last Will and Testament of Saunders Welch. (manuscript copy), 1775 December 10; 4 pages; 23 x 14 cm. (Box 1-120)
  Welch, Saunders, 1710 or 11-1784
- G. Beaumont. John Hoppner, R.A. W.C. Edwards., undated; engraving; 12.5 x 10 cm. (Box 1-129)
  Portrait of George Howland Beaumont.
  Engravings; Beaumont, George Howland, Sir, 1753-1827
- Lieut. Gen. Sir Eyre Coote. K.B. K.C. and M.P. Engraved for the Military Panorama by T. Bonnor from a miniature by W. Hanes. London, Published April 17, 1813 by L. Martin 198 Oxford Street., 1813 April 17; engraving; 20.5 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-131)
  Portrait of Sir Eyre Coote.
  Engravings; Coote, Eyre, Sir, 1726-1783
- Untitled and unidentified portrait, perhaps of Nathaniel Hone., undated; etching; 7 x 6 cm. (Box 1-132)
  Etchings; Hone, Nathaniel, 1718-1784
- Van Dyck (Antoine) Peintre 1641., undated; engraving; 24.5 x 18 cm. (Box 1-133)
  Portrait of Sir Anthony Van Dyck.
  Engravings; Van Dyck, Anthony, 1599-1641
- Sir Joshua Reynolds. From the original picture painted by himself in the council room of the Royal Academy. Drawn by M. Haughton, engraved by H. Meyer. Published May 8, 1809 by T. Cadell & W. Davies Strand London., 1809 May 8; engraving; 28.5 x 20 cm. (Box 1-134)
  Portrait of Sir Joshua Reynolds.
  Engravings; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792
- Wm Chambers. Sir Joshua Reynolds. W.C. Edwards., undated; engraving; 13 x 10 cm. (Box 1-138)
  Portrait of Sir William Chambers.
  Engravings; Chambers, William, Sir, 1723-1796
- Mr. Garrick in the character of Richard IIIrd. Painted by Wm. Hogarth. Engraved by Geo. Cooke., undated; engraving; 12.5 x 15 cm. (Box 1-149)
- His Royal Highness George, Prince of Wales. Engraved by W. Read, from a painting by Cosway R.A. London, Richard Bentley, 1836; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-152)
  Portrait of George IV.
  Engravings; George, King of Great Britain, IV, 1762-1830
- Hampton House, The Seat of Mrs. Garrick. Engraved by W. Radcliffe from a drawing by J.P. Neale for the Beauties of England & Wales., undated; engraving; 11 x 15 cm. (Box 1-153)
  View of Hampton House.
  Engravings; Garrick's Villa (Richmond upon Thames, London, England)